So, let's unfold the model in time,
我们来基于时间展开模型
and clean the sketch a bit,
清洁一下概略图
and focus on the third time step.
重点关注第三个时间步长
In this model, we have three weight matrices that we want to modify.
在这个模型中 我们有三个想要修正的权重矩阵
The weight matrix Wx linking the network inputs to the state or the hidden layer,
权重矩阵 Wx 连接网络的输入和状态或隐藏层
the weight matrix Ws connecting one stage to the next,
权重矩阵 Ws 连接一个状态和下一个状态
and the weight matrix Wy connecting this data to the output.
权重矩阵 Wy 连接这个状态和输出
Let's start with adjusting Wy,
我们首先调整 Wy
which is the most straightforward to obtain.
这是最容易得到的
At time T equals 3,
现在时间 t+3
the derivative of the squared error with respect to
对于 Wy 平方差的偏导数
Wy is found by a simple one step chain rule,
可以通过一步链式法则得到结果
and equals to the derivative of the squared error with respect to the output,
等于输出平方差的偏导数
multiplied by the derivative of the output with respect to the weight matrix Wy.
乘以权重矩阵 Wy 输出的导数
As always, these derivatives will be
与之前一样 根据权重矩阵的每个要素
calculated according to each element of the weight matrix.
计算得到这些导数
To adjust the other two matrices,
为了调整其他两个矩阵
we will need to use Backpropagation Through Time,
我们需要使用基于时间的反向传播算法
and it doesn't matter which one we choose to adjust first.
我们选择首先调整哪个 并不会产生影响
Let's choose to focus on the weight matrix Ws,
我们来重点关注权重矩阵 Ws
the weight matrix connecting one state to the next,
这个权重矩阵连接一个状态和下一个状态
and remove anything we don't need from the sketch.
并且删除概略图中我们不需要的内容
At first glance, it may seem that when finding the derivative with respect to Ws,
乍一看 这像是找到 Ws 导数时
we only need to consider state S3.
我们只需要考虑状态 S3
This way the derivative of timestep, T equals 3,
这样 t 等于 3 时间步长的导数
simply equals the derivative of the squared error with respect to the output,
等于输出平方差的偏导数
multiplied by the derivative of the output with respect to S3,
乘以 S3 输出的导数
and multiplied by the derivative of S3 with respect to the Matrix Ws.
乘以权重矩阵 Ws S3 的导数
But S3 also depends on S2 and S1 the previous states.
不过 S3 取决于之前的状态 S1 和 S2
So, we can't really stop there.
实际上我们不能到此为止
We also need to take into account,
我们也需要考虑
what has happened before,
之前发生的事情
and add to that contribution to our calculation.
把这个贡献添加到我们计算中
So, we will continue calculating the gradient,
所以我们会继续计算梯度
knowing that we need to accumulate the contributions,
认识到我们需要累加
originating from each of the previous states.
之前每个状态的贡献
When we consider S2,
我们考虑 S2 时
we have the following path contributing to the backpropagation.
以下路径会贡献反向传播算法
We can clearly see that S3 depends on S2,
显然我们发现 S3 依赖 S2
giving us the derivative calculations using the chain rule,
使用链式法则计算导数
all the way back to the derivative of S2 with respect to the matrix Ws.
追溯到权重矩阵 Ws S2 的导数
But we're not done yet,
不过我们并没结束
we need to go one more step back to the first state S1,
我们需要再回到第一个状态 S1
giving us the calculations again by using the chain rule,
再次使用链式法则计算导数
all the way back to the derivative of S1 with respect to the matrix Ws.
追溯到权重矩阵 Ws S1 的导数
So, let's look again at
通过使用基于时间的反向传播算法
the accumulative gradient we now have by using Backpropagation Through Time,
我们再次观察得到的累积梯度
which we calculated considering all the state vectors that we have,
即我们要考虑所有的状态向量
state vector S3, state vector S2,
状态向量 S3 状态向量 S2
and state vector S1.
和状态向量 S1
Generally, speaking we consider multiple time steps back,
一般说来 我们追溯多个时间步长
and need a general framework to define Backpropagation Through Time,
需要一个通用框架定义基于时间的反向传播算法
for the purpose of changing Ws.
来改变 Ws
So, what's next?
那么接下来是什么呢？
In our next video we will focus on adjusting the weight matrix Wx.
在接下来的视频中 我们会重点关注调整权重矩阵 Wx